(triumphant music)
- [Voiceover] Hey and welcome!
I'm Hammeh, and in this series,
we're discovering the lore,
back story and characters
of Overwatch's heroes,
including more detail
through their in-game voice
lines and interactions.
Before any map starts during
the game on various triggers,
Overwatch heroes chatter
with and react to each other
in some funny in-game voice interactions.
These give us some great insights
into hero character,
interests and back stories.
In this video, we're
looking at Junkrat's story
through his interactions
with fellow heroes
or villains and the world around him.
An explosive obsessed freak who lives
to cause chaos and destruction,
Junkrat is currently on the run
with his partner in crime, Roadhog,
causing chaos around the world.
Slightly radiation tinged and unhinged
from his time as a Junker,
Junkrat holds a valuable secret
that bounty hunters and
nefarious individuals
are hunting him for.
Whether we'll find out what it is in time
remains to be seen.
Firstly, we'll quickly run
through Junkrat's story.
The first Omnic Crisis affected lives
all around the world.
When defunct, dismantled omniums,
massive factories of automated
construction machines
and self-improving software algorithms
built by the Omnica Corporation,
decided to wake themselves back up,
they launched a military campaign
against all of humanity.
Australia wasn't spared.
In the peace agreements
following the crisis,
government officials gifted
the Australian omnium
and the surrounding area to the Omnics
that nearly destroyed their country,
hoping to establish a
longtime peace accord.
This arrangement permanently
displaced a large number
of the Outback's residents,
a scattered collection of
survivalists, solar farmers and people
who just wanted to be left alone.
Furious over the loss of their homes,
this group turned to violent rebellion.
Events escalated until the rebels
sabotaged the omnium's fusion core,
resulting in an explosion
that destroyed the facility,
irradiated the region
and littered the Outback
with twisted metal and
wreckage for kilometers around.
Some people survived.
Calling themselves the Junkers,
they scavenged the husk of the omnium
and formed a lawless, cutthroat
society in its shadow.
Junkrat was one of them.
He eked out a living by reclaiming metal
and components from the ruins.
Like many others, he was affected
by the lingering radiation.
This touch of madness made him ideal
for handling dangerous explosives,
a love which he's turned into a bit
of an obsession, it's safe to say.
Junkrat would have been
just another casualty
of the war if he hadn't shot to notoriety
when he discovered an
extremely valuable secret
in the bones of the Australian omnium.
Few know the nature of what he's found,
but he was pursued by bounty hunters,
gangs and opportunists, wherever he went,
until he struck a deal
with the Junker enforcer, Roadhog.
Roadhog grudgingly bodyguards Junkrat
in exchange for a 50-50
share of the spoils,
probably the only reason he puts up
with the explosive obsessive.
Now Roadhog in tow, Junkrat
has left the Outback
and embarked upon an
international crime spree,
leaving nothing but havoc
and bedlam in his wake.
So far, we've seen the pair
in the UK. and King's Row
stealing the Crown Jewels,
robbing in a vault in Dorado, Mexico,
and even breaking into
ice cream trucks in Paris
and robbing arcade toys
in what might be Hanamura, Japan.
We also know that Junkrat
and Roadhog have been
to Sydney, as detailed in their comic,
Going Legit, at some point,
when what they thought
was a legitimate job
turned out to be a setup,
they got an explosive revenge
with the presumed death of the CEO
or a senior member of a
company called Hyde Global,
as well as destroying a building
in Sydney central business district.
Even with a motto of no job too big,
no score too small is there any reason
for this trail of destruction and mayhem?
Does it have anything to do
with the treasure that Junkrat's hiding?
Or are the two just,
well, enjoying themselves?
With this mad pair, you
probably can't tell?
- [Junkrat] It's a perfect
day for some mayhem!
- [Voiceover] As you might expect
for a crazy, explosive obsessive,
Junkrat loves nothing more than talking
about his favorite hobby.
And that, of course, is blowing things up.
- [Junkrat] You look like the kind of guy
who could use something blown up!
It's hard to just sit around,
knowing there's someone out there
that needs to be blown up!
If at first you don't succeed,
blow it up again!
Oh, don't mind me.
I was just taking five.
Definitely not thinking
about blowing something up.
No way!
(laughs)
Definitely not!
Okay, come on, maybe
just a little something?
- [Voiceover] And when he's
not talking about his vocation,
Junkrat's doing his second favorite thing
or things in the world.
Those are cracking bad
jokes and throwing insults.
- [Junkrat] I've got a
leg up on the competition.
Blew up just one.
Don't you come the raw prawn with me!
Ah, aiming's overrated.
Outta my face, ya drongo!
- [Voiceover] While we're
on the subject of bad jokes,
Junkrat loves to mock just
about anything and anyone.
Stay tuned for a mini Junkrat quiz.
Can you guess what
Junkrat is taking the mick
out of in each of these lines?
I'll give you the answers after each one.
- [Junkrat] Baby, I'm a firework!
- [Voiceover] That, of
course, is Katy Perry
with her Firework song.
- [Junkrat] And on that bombshell.
- [Voiceover] That, of course, is
Top Gear Jeremy Clarkson's
old sign off line
at the end of every episode.
- [Junkrat] Now, that's a knife!
- [Voiceover] The infamous
knife scene in Crocodile Dundee,
when they compare the
size of their knives.
- [Junkrat] If I had PhD,
they'd call me Dr. Boom!
- [Voiceover] Of course,
that's Dr. Boom from Area 52,
Netherstorm in World of Warcraft,
and since known as Dr. Balanced
or Dr. Seven in Hearthstone.
- [Junkrat] Time is money, friends.
And we're almost flat broke!
Attack!
- [Voiceover] Time is money,
friends is a direct reference
to the goblins in World of Warcraft.
They say it all the time
when you click on them.
Now, the last one of these
is really impressive.
Thanks to our guest voiceover
for spotting this one.
Where'd you think this music is from?
Or how it's referring to Junkrat?
♫ Dum, dum, dum, dum, dum
♫ Dum, dum, dum, dum, dum ♫
Now, I don't think that's in-game,
but according to our guest voiceover,
it's in V for Vendetta.
Hugo Weaving actually wears
a Guy Fawkes mask throughout the film.
And this music is used in the final scene
where the Houses of
Parliament get blown up.
Spoiler.
Do, of course, remember
that Junkrat's name is Jamison Fawkes.
Guy Fawkes blowing stuff up.
Finally, this music is also used
in some fireworks displays
and you can see fireworks with music.
So, multiple different references there
in that little bit of music,
very, very cool.
Cheers to our guest voiceover
for spotting that one.
Junkrat and Roadhog by knowing each other
don't have huge connections
with the other cast
of Overwatch at the moment.
But that does not stop Junkrat
from liberally chatting
to and in some cases,
mocking a lot of them.
As we know, Junkrat and
Roadhog are literally
as thick as thieves.
Roadhog's in it for the
money, guarding Junkrat
for a half share of his treasure.
And the two make quite the double act
on some occasions.
Junkrat has a very literal view
of the pair's relationship sometimes.
- [Junkrat] You hook 'em, I'll cook 'em.
- [Voiceover] And when
Roadhog asks Junkrat
to stay out of trouble,
Junkrat swears he will.
Maybe Roadhog's the father
figure in this team up.
- [Junkrat] I'll be on me best behavior.
- [Voiceover] Apparently,
Roadhog comes out
with the odd joke even,
according to Junkrat.
- [Junkrat] You won't
believe the joke old pig face
over there told me the other day.
Huh, Roadhog?
- [Voiceover] Ultimately,though,
we know Roadhog's
a man of few words.
When Junkrat sees an allied Roadhog
getting a kill on his team,
he expresses his thanks.
- [Junkrat] I knew there was
a reason I kept you around.
And it wasn't the sparkling conversation.
- [Voiceover] Whatever barbs
he throws Roadhog's way,
Junkrat does care about
the fate of his bodyguard.
When a Roadhog gets
killed on the same team
as a Junkrat, you might be able
to hear this line, I think.
- [Junkrat] Ay, I'm the only one
who gets to kill the big lug!
- [Voiceover] And I have no idea
when this line triggers,
but it's kind of touching
for Junkrat to say this to Roadhog.
Don't you think?
- [Junkrat] I could
always count on you, mate!
- [Voiceover] Junkrat has a
few interactions with Mei.
Even if he's trying to be
polite and make conversation,
Mei doesn't really want to
have anything to do with him.
- [Junkrat] I get cold just lookin' at ya.
- [Mei] Then, you should
look somewhere else.
- [Voiceover] And when
Mei criticizes Junkrat,
his usual wit comes to his defense.
Take your own pun medicine, Mei!
- [Mei] You're just a no good bully!
How can you even look at
yourself in the mirror?
- [Junkrat] That's cold!
- [Voiceover] As one of
the faces of Overwatch,
Tracer is a prime target
for Junkrat's quips.
Even her trademark catchphrase isn't safe.
- [Junkrat] Cheers, mate!
The cavalry's here.
- [Tracer] That's my line.
- [Voiceover] Now, Junkrat
probably regrets his rudeness
when his curiosity about
explosives gets the better of him.
- [Junkrat] Think I could have a look
at one of those bombs of yours?
- [Voiceover] As we've seen from his bio,
Junkrat's no fan of Omnics.
And I think this line triggers
when he either gets hit or discord orbed
from an enemy Zenyatta.
There's a couple of variations.
- [Junkrat] Piece of junk!
- [Voiceover] Junkrat even finds it funny
when he sees one of himself.
- [Junkrat] He looks familiar.
Hey, that's me!
- [Voiceover] And finally, I'm not sure
of the trigger for this,
or if it's in-game,
but it's kind of interesting to see
how Junkrat sees himself anyway.
- [Junkrat] I beg your pardon!
I consider myself a freedom fighter,
a misunderstood one.
- [Voiceover] In the
last of our interactions,
there's a couple of interactions
with other heroes around
Junkrat's treasure.
Now, I don't have the lines on me,
but Hanzo and apparently Reaper,
but both ask him about his treasure
with Hanzo saying you
couldn't possibly keep it
on your person, apparently.
Junkrat has a couple of responses
to the two different individuals.
Here's one of them.
- [Hanzo] Where did
you hide your treasure?
You could hardly have it on your person.
- [Junkrat] Treasure?
Sure I don't know anything
you're talking about!
- [Voiceover] When it comes
to the world of Overwatch,
we know that Junkrat and
Roadhog from their crime spree
are pretty well-traveled
since leaving the Outback.
So naturally, Junkrat's got a bunch to say
on several maps.
The tension between Omnics and humans
in King's Row strikes a cord with Junkrat.
He's, of course, had tensions with Omnics
in his own life, too.
Here's what he says when
he spawns on King's Row.
- [Junkrat] So, we're delivering a bomb
to scrap some bots, and
I'm getting paid for it.
My kind of job.
- [Voiceover] And as we've
seen in the Moment in Crime,
the video about Junkrat and Roadhog,
the two actually stole the Crown Jewels
or definitely did some kind of heist here.
And both of them will reminisce fondly
about it in a couple of different ways.
- [Junkrat] Ah, remember that time
we stole the Crown Jewels.
All hail King Jamison Fawkes the First.
And, uh, Duke Roadhog?
What is your name anyways?
God save the king!
(laughs)
- [Voiceover] Numbani, of
course, is meant to be the city
where Omnics and humans
live together in harmony.
And Junkrat naturally is
a little bit skeptical
to say the least about this.
- [Junkrat] This place is the worst!
Let's turn it into one big scrap heap.
- [Voiceover] Really no fan of Omnics,
as we can see several times.
Dorado is quite closely linked
to Junkrat and Roadhog.
There's a whole bunch of evidence showing
that they've robbed the bank,
their faces on the
monitors here, for example,
the bank heist map in the level
that was also shown at Blizzcon 2015,
I think in the lower panel,
and the sprays of Junkrat and Roadhog,
if you're very quick, that you can see
in Soldier: 76's Hero short, on this wall.
For my review of that short,
check out the video on
the channel, linked below.
Of course, when Junkrat returns
to the scene of the crime,
he does have a little reminisce
and maybe wonders if he
needs a little bit more
liquid cash assets, shall we say.
- [Junkrat] Hey, me old tunnel!
Might be time to make another withdrawal.
- [Voiceover] Junkrat's no fan of Omnics,
as we've seen in his
comic and in other lines,
so visiting the home of
the Shambali in Nepal
is naturally not going to
be to his liking at all.
There's a couple of different lines
associated with here,
when Junkrat spawns and maybe another one
I think as well.
- [Junkrat] If these bots
wanna go into the light,
I'd be more than happy to help.
Now this place, bah, makes
me wanna be an atheist.
- [Voiceover] Whatever his
feelings towards Omnics,
Junkrat always defaults back
to his trademark,
uh, entrepreneurship?
He sees the business opportunities
on the Temple of Anubis, sure enough,
when you spawn him, as you should be able
to hear here.
(gun fires)
- [Junkrat] You think there's something
worth stealing in that temple?
- [Voiceover] Junkrat's
always appreciative
of fellow craftsmen.
When I say craftsmen, I mean people
who can create chaos and destruction.
And I think that this one
may well be on Route 66
when he's looking at the right truck.
- [Junkrat] Wow, look at this!
My hat's off to the architect
of this fantastic destruction!
- [Voiceover] And finally,
for fun, not heard this,
but perhaps it's when Junkrat passes one
of the coffee shops in-game.
Has anyone heard this one?
- [Junkrat] Can you do a flat white?
No, how 'bout I flatten the place?
- [Voiceover] Thanks very much for tuning
into my hero voice line and story series.
Check out the playlist
linked here on the left
for more videos like
this of different heroes.
If you liked this video,
please hit that Like button,
subscribe, comment, share it on social.
And let me know what you thought,
what lines you enjoyed most
and any heroes you'd
like to see covered next.
I really appreciate
hearing what you all think.
Until next time, I've been Hammeh.
Take it easy.
(intense music)